Guide to the Edwin Richard Weinerman Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Medical, Political, and Social Activities and Organizations, Series III; 3.75 linear feet (9 boxes)
  The material in the third series, MEDICAL, POLITICAL, AND SOCIAL ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS, falls into two sections. The first section is a file of material relating to professional or medical organizations that Weinerman belonged to. These are arranged alphabetically by the name of the organization. The second section contains material relating to Weinerman's broader political and social concerns. This material is organized under the name of the relevant organization or general subject. At the end of this series is an extensive file of articles, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and the like, on nuclear radiation hazards and on smog and air pollution.
  - Alameda-Contra Costa Medical Association, Medical Services Committee (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Alameda-Contra Costa Medical Association, Physicians' Round Table Discussion Series (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - American Medical Association (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - American Public Health Association (Box 48, Folder 4-5)
  - American Public Health Association, Western Branch (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Association of Internes and Medical Students (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Association of Teachers of Preventive Medicine (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Association of Teachers of Preventive Medicine, Committee on Medical Care Teaching (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Berkeley Mental Health Association (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Committee for National Health Insurance (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care (Box 49, Folder 12-13)
  - The Delta Omega Society (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Co-operative Health Federation of America (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - American Labor Health Association (Box 49, Folder 16-17)
  - Group Health Association of America (Box 49, Folder 18-19)
  - International Academy of Legal Medicine and Social Medicine (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Medical Committee for Human Rights (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Medical Committee for Human Rights, Health Rights News (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - Medical Committee for Human Rights, newspaper clippings and pamphlets (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Medico-Chirugical Society (Box 50, Folder 24-25)
  - Northern California Public Health Association (Box 50, Folder 26)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, Newsletter (Box 50, Folder 28)
  - The Physicians Forum (Box 50, Folder 29-31)
  - Committee on Social Security for Physicians of the Physicians Forum (Box 51, Folder 32-33)
  - Planned Parenthood League of Alameda County (Box 51, Folder 34)
  - Society of Social Medicine (Box 51, Folder 35)
  - misc. professional organizations (Box 51, Folder 36)
  - East Bay Committee for American Activities (anti-Velde Committee) (Box 51, Folder 37)
  - East Bay Community Forum (Box 51, Folder 38)
  - East Bay Physicians' Committee for Civil Liberties (Box 51, Folder 39)
  - Federation for Repeal of the Levering Act (Box 51, Folder 40)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities, articles and newspaper clippings (Box 51, Folder 41)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities, pamphlets, advertisements (Box 51, Folder 42)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities, misc. (Box 51, Folder 43)
  - University of California loyalty oath controversy, articles and pamphlets re: oaths and academic freedom (Box 52, Folder 44-45)
  - University of California loyalty oath controversy, newspaper clippings (Box 52, Folder 46)
  - Smith Act Committee (Box 52, Folder 47)
  - California Conference of Social Work (Box 52, Folder 48)
  - California Democratic Council, Issues Conference Reports, 1960-1962 (Box 52, Folder 49-50)
  - California Democratic Council, papers re: issue and platform statements, 1957, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 51-52)
  - California Democratic Council, papers re: issue and platform statements, 1960-1961 (Box 53, Folder 53-54)
  - California Democratic Council, pamphlets, programs, and newspaper clippings (Box 53, Folder 55)
  - The Commonwealth Club of California (Box 53, Folder 56)
  - Connecticut Scientists, Engineers and Physicians for Johnson and Humphrey (Box 53, Folder 57)
  - Cook for Congress campaign, statement on health needs (Box 53, Folder 58)
  - Council of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions (Box 53, Folder 59)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 53, Folder 60)
  - Save the World Committee ( The Liberal Democrat ) (Box 53, Folder 61)
  - Scientists' Committee for Radiation Information, speakers' materials and newsletters (Box 53, Folder 62)
  - Society for Social Responsibility in Science (Box 53, Folder 63)
  - Jeremiah Stamler, M.D. Legal Aid Fund (Box 53, Folder 64)
  - Viet Nam, protest petitions and advertisements (Box 53, Folder 65)
  - articles re: air pollution and smog, 1954-1960, undated (Box 54, Folder 66-73)
  - Contra Costa County Health Department Bulletins re: air pollution and smog (Box 54, Folder 74)
  - newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and misc. re: air pollution and smog (Box 54, Folder 75)
  - article re: biological and chemical weapons (Box 54, Folder 76)
  - articles re: nuclear weapons and radiation hazards, 1955-1959 (Box 54, Folder 77-82)
  - articles re: nuclear weapons and radiation hazards, 1960-1965, undated (Box 55, Folder 83-89)
  - newspaper clippings re: nuclear weapons and radiation hazards (Box 55, Folder 90)
  - pamphlets re: nuclear weapons and radiation hazards (Box 55, Folder 91-92)
  - pamphlets re: nuclear weapons and radiation hazards (Box 56, Folder 93-95)
  - press releases, statements re: nuclear weapons and radiation hazards (Box 56, Folder 96-97)
  - memoranda re: suits to halt nuclear testing (Box 56, Folder 98)
  - misc. advertisements and pamphlets (Box 56, Folder 99)
- Addresses and Writings, 1939-1940, 1942, 1945-1946, 1948-1969, undated; Series IV; 4.5 linear feet (10 boxes)
  The fourth series, ADDRESSES AND WRITINGS, is arranged alphabetically by title. When a folder contains only notes for an address or talk, this is indicated by the word notes in parentheses after the title.
  This series also contains some scripts of radio broadcasts made by Weinerman and some articles written by Weinerman for a newspaper press service. These are placed after the alphabetically arranged file of addresses and writings. Filed at the end of the series, is an article written by Weinerman's wife, Shirley (Basch) Weinerman.
  - "Academic Freedom and the Community" (notes), 1949 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - "Accident-Proneness: A Critique", 1949 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - "Air Pollution" (notes), 1958 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - "Air Pollution in California" (notes), 1959 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - "Ambulatory Medical Care in the Teaching Center", 1963 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - "An Ambulatory Service Data System" by M. H. Brenner and E. R. Weinerman, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - "Ambulatory Service in the Teaching Hospital" by E. R. Weinerman and W. A. Steiger, 1964 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - "The Anatomy of Anxiety", 1955 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - "Anchor Points Underlying the Planning for Tomorrow's Health Care", 1965 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - "An Appraisal of Medical Care in Group Health Centers", 1955-1956 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - "Appraisal of Medical Care Programs", 1950 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - "As Others See Us: the Patient's Viewpoint", 1963 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - "As Others See Us: the Patient's Viewpoint" (printed in the Proceedings of the 13th Group Health Institute), 1963 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - "As Others See Us: the Patient's Viewpoint" (various printed excerpts), 1963-1964 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - "Patients' Perceptions of Group Medical Care" (revised version of "As Others See Us"), 1963 (Box 58, Folder 15)
  - "To See Ourselves" (early version of "As Others See Us"?), 1963 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  - "Burns-Chapel Bills" (notes), 1955 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  - "The California Disability Insurance Program", 1949? (Box 58, Folder 18)
  - "The Case Against Civil Defense" (notes), 1961 (Box 58, Folder 19)
  - "Changes in Medical Practice - Implications for Ambulatory Services of Hospitals", 1965 (Box 58, Folder 20)
  - "The Changing Pattern of Rheumatic Fever", 1955 (Box 58, Folder 21)
  - "Changing Patterns in Hospital Emergency Service", 1964 (Box 58, Folder 22)
  - Civil liberties (notes), undated (Box 58, Folder 23)
  - "Cleveland Health Foundation: Planning and Organization", 1963 (Box 58, Folder 24)
  - "Community Health Centers: Progress and Prospects" (notes), 1964 (Box 58, Folder 25)
  - "Competition and Co-operation in Health Service", 1953 (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - "The Control of Tuberculosis Among Medical Students" by E. R. Weinerman and F. O. Coe, 1942 (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - "Current Health Insurance Proposals" (notes), 1949 (Box 58, Folder 28)
  - "Development of Health Insurance and Medical Programs and Their Effect Upon Cost, Quality, and Organization of Medical Care", 1960 (Box 58, Folder 29)
  - "Development of Medical Care Plans in the U.S." (notes), 1959 (Box 58, Folder 30)
  - "Doctor, Meet the Working Man" (notes), 1949 (Box 58, Folder 31)
  - "Dr. Weinerman on Health Flans" (summary of remarks to convention of The California Federation of Teachers), 1953 (Box 58, Folder 32)
  - "Early Diagnosis in a Group Practice Medical Center", 1955 (Box 59, Folder 33)
  - "Essentials of a Successful Group Health Plan", 1951 (Box 59, Folder 34)
  - "Evaluation of Medical Care Plans" (notes), 1959, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 35)
  - evaluation of medical needs (notes), undated (Box 59, Folder 36)
  - "Fallout and Bomb Testing" (notes), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 37)
  - "Financing Medical Care" (notes), 1959 (Box 59, Folder 38)
  - "Forces Shaping Public Health Today", 1956 (Box 59, Folder 39)
  - "Future of Medical Practice" (notes), 1961 (Box 59, Folder 40)
  - "The Group Health Co-operative of Puget Sound: Report of a Study", 1950 (Box 59, Folder 41)
  - "Group Medical Practice" (notes), 1955 (Box 59, Folder 42)
  - "Group Medical Practice", 1963 (Box 59, Folder 43)
  - "Group Practice Revisited", 1969 (Box 59, Folder 44)
  - "Group Practice and Union Health Centers", 1958 (Box 59, Folder 45)
  - "Group Practice and Union Health Centers" (printed in Papers and Proceedings of the National Conference on Labor Health Services), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 46)
  - "The Growing Crisis in Medical Services and Medical Education" (notes and background materials from a conference on this subject), 1966 (Box 59, Folder 47)
  - "Health Aspects of Smog" (notes), 1957 (Box 59, Folder 48)
  - "Health of the Business Agent: Tensions" (notes), [1958] (Box 59, Folder 49)
  - "Health Effects" [of air pollution] (notes), undated (Box 59, Folder 50)
  - "Health in Europe" (notes), 1950 (Box 59, Folder 51)
  - "The Health of Farm Migrants" by S. J. Axelrod and E. R. Weinerman, undated (Box 59, Folder 52)
  - "Health Hazards of Radiation from Nuclear Weapons"(notes), 1959 (Box 59, Folder 53)
  - "Health Insurance: Pitfall or Progress", 1954 (Box 59, Folder 54)
  - "Health Maintenance in Prepaid Group Practice" by J. H. Sloss, W. R. Young, and E. R. Weinerman, 1968 (Box 59, Folder 55)
  - "Health and Medical Care" (notes), 1960 (Box 59, Folder 56)
  - "Health and Medical Care in the Urban Ghetto" (notes), 1968 (Box 59, Folder 57)
  - "Health Program for California Democrats" (notes), 1958 (Box 59, Folder 58)
  - "Health and Society" (notes), undated (Box 59, Folder 59)
  - "Health and Welfare Plans" (notes), 1954 (Box 59, Folder 60)
  - health and welfare plans (notes), 1956 (Box 59, Folder 61)
  - "Housing and Health" (radio interview), 1950 (Box 59, Folder 62)
  - "Implications for Schools of Public Health in the Establishment and Staffing of Regional Medical Programs", 1966 (Box 60, Folder 64)
  - "Industrial Health and Medical Care Programs" (prepared for Summer Labor Institute on health and welfare plans), 1951 (Box 60, Folder 65)
  - "Institutional and Social Care for the Arthritic" by R. M. Acheson, A. Crago, and E. R. Weinerman, undated (Box 60, Folder 66)
  - introduction to "Medical Care: the Current Scene and Prospects for the Future", 1969 (Box 60, Folder 67)
  - "Investigating Committees and Universities", 1953 (Box 60, Folder 68)
  - "Key Health Issues in California" (notes), 1958 (Box 60, Folder 69)
  - "Labor and the Hospitals" (notes), 1952 (Box 60, Folder 70)
  - "Labor and Medicine", (notes) (Box 60, Folder 71)
  - "Labor Plans for Health", 1952 (Box 60, Folder 72)
  - "Labor's Interest in Occupational Health and Medical Care", 1960 (Box 60, Folder 73)
  - "Liberalism in Medicine" (notes), 1960 (Box 60, Folder 74)
  - "Light Versus Heat", 1950 (Box 60, Folder 75)
  - "Major Health Issues Facing Labor in an Election Year" (notes), 1958 (Box 60, Folder 76)
  - "Man and the Atomic Age" (notes), 1949 (Box 60, Folder 77)
  - "Man and the Atomic Age" (transcript of series of seminars), 1949 March-April (Box 60, Folder 78)
  - "Man and the Atomic Age" (transcript of series of seminars), 1949 May-June (Box 60, Folder 79)
  - "Medical Aspects of Heart Disease" (notes), 1954 (Box 60, Folder 80)
  - "Medical Care - Focus on the Patient", 1962 (Box 60, Folder 81)
  - "Medical Care for the Future" (notes), 1958 (Box 60, Folder 82)
  - "Medical Care, 1961: Problems and Portents" (notes) (Box 60, Folder 83)
  - "Medical Care: Patterns and Perspectives", 1951 (Box 61, Folder 84)
  - "Medical Care Plans" (notes), 1956 (Box 61, Folder 85)
  - medical care plans for union members, 1949 (Box 61, Folder 86)
  - "Medical Care Problems" (notes), 1954 (Box 61, Folder 87)
  - "Medical Care and Public Health: Two Worlds or One?", 1964 (Box 61, Folder 88)
  - "Medical Care and Rural Life" by C. F. Brannan and E. R. Weinerman, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 89)
  - "Medical Care in the Territory of Hawaii", 1952 (Box 61, Folder 90)
  - "Medical Economics" (notes), 1956 (Box 61, Folder 91)
  - "Medical Education and Community Needs", 1962 (Box 61, Folder 92)
  - "Medical Effects of Atomic Radiation" (notes), 1957 (Box 61, Folder 93)
  - "Medical Group Practice in California" (early drafts) (Box 61, Folder 94)
  - "Medical Group Practice in California" by E. R. Weinerman and G. S. Goldstein, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 95)
  - "Medical Group Practice in California", 1952 (Box 61, Folder 96)
  - "Medical Group Practice in California" (background material and notes) (Box 61, Folder 97)
  - "Medical Monopoly", undated (Box 62, Folder 98)
  - "Medical Schools and the Quality of Medical Care", 1948 (Box 62, Folder 99)
  - "Medicine and Community: New Patterns at Yale-New Haven Medical Center" (background paper for the H.E.W. Secretary's Regional Conference on Health Care Costs), 1968 (Box 62, Folder 100)
  - "The Menance of 'Buzz-Bomb Juice' - Methyl Alcohol Poisoning Among U.S. Troops", undated (Box 62, Folder 101)
  - "Methodology of a Family Health Study" by. C. F. Muller, A. Waybur, and E. R. Weinerman, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 102)
  - "Multiphasic Screening" (notes), 1956 (Box 62, Folder 103)
  - "Multiphasic Screening of Longshoremen with Organized Medical Follow-Up" by E. R. Weinerman, L. Breslow, N. D. Belloc, A. Waybur, and B. K. Milmore, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 104)
  - "Needs of Children as Related to Fears and Tensions in the Modern World" (notes), 1957 (Box 62, Folder 105)
  - "New Ideas in Health Care" (notes), 1955 (Box 62, Folder 106)
  - "New Ideas in Health Service", 1955 February-November (Box 62, Folder 107-108)
  - "New Medicine for New Environments" (radio interview), 1967 (Box 62, Folder 109)
  - "New Patterns in Industrial Health and Medical Care Programs in California" by E. R. Weinerman and H. K. Abrams, 1950 (Box 62, Folder 110)
  - "New Patterns of Social Medicine at Yale", 1968 (Box 62, Folder 111)
  - "'Non-Geographical' Group Practice in Health Service Regions", 1949 (Box 62, Folder 112)
  - "Nuclear Hazards" (notes), 1959 (Box 62, Folder 113)
  - "Nuclear Weapons" (notes), 1959 (Box 62, Folder 114)
  - "Nuclear Weapons and the Medical Profession" (notes), 1958 (Box 62, Folder 115)
  - "The Organization of Health Services in Eastern Europe", 1967 (Box 62, Folder 116)
  - "The Periodic Health Checkup", 1956 (Box 63, Folder 117)
  - "The Permanente Health Plan", 1951 (Box 63, Folder 118)
  - "The Physician and Labor Health Plans", 1958 (Box 63, Folder 119)
  - "Planning for Medical Care" (notes), 1949 (Box 63, Folder 120)
  - "Planning and Organization of the Connecticut Regional Medical Program", 1967 (Box 63, Folder 121)
  - "Pretenses, Practices and Patterns in Group Health Programs", 1962 (Box 63, Folder 122)
  - "Pretenses, Practices and Patterns in Group Health Programs" (printed in the Proceedings of the 12th Group Health Institute), 1962 (Box 63, Folder 123)
  - "The Problem of Male Supremacy" (notes), 1956 (Box 63, Folder 124)
  - "The Problem of Smog" (notes), 1956 (Box 63, Folder 125)
  - "The Problems of Aging" (notes), 1958, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 126)
  - "The Problems of Medical Care - A Review", 1949 (Box 63, Folder 127)
  - "Problems and Perspectives of Group Practice", 1968 (Box 63, Folder 128)
  - "Prospectus for Medical Care - Twenty-first Century", 1967 (Box 63, Folder 129)
  - psychiatric care (notes), 1960 (Box 63, Folder 130)
  - "Public Health Comes of Age", undated (Box 63, Folder 131)
  - "Public Health and Medical Care in Hawaii", 1953 (Box 63, Folder 132)
  - "Public Health in a Nuclear Age" (notes), 1959 (Box 63, Folder 133)
  - "Quality Control in Prepaid Group Practice Programs", 1961 (Box 63, Folder 134)
  - "The Quality of Medical Care", 1951 (Box 63, Folder 135)
  - "The Quality of Medical Care" (printed in the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science), 1951 (Box 64, Folder 136)
  - "The Quality of Medical Care in a National Health Program", 1949 (Box 64, Folder 137)
  - "Radiation Safety and the Atomic Energy Commission", 1960 (Box 64, Folder 138)
  - "Recent Trends in Medical Care" (notes), 1949 (Box 64, Folder 139)
  - "Regionalization of Medical Services", 1949 (Box 64, Folder 140)
  - "Research into the Organization of Medical Practice", 1966 (Box 64, Folder 141)
  - "The Returning Medical Veteran", 1945-1946 (Box 64, Folder 142)
  - review of The Coming Revolution in Medicine, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 143)
  - review of Doctors' Offices in Hospital Financed Buildings, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 144)
  - review of The Expanding Role of Ambulatory Services in Hospitals and Health Departments, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 145)
  - review of Health and Medical Care in New York City, 1957 (Box 64, Folder 146)
  - review of A Report on the Family Health Maintenance Demonstration, 1964 (Box 64, Folder 147)
  - "The Role of the Interdisciplinary Team - Medicine", 1965 (Box 64, Folder 148)
  - "Role of the Medical Schools", 1948 (Box 64, Folder 149)
  - "The Role of Nursing in Medical Care Plans" (notes), 1957 (Box 64, Folder 150)
  - "Rural Prepayment Medical Care Plans and Public Health Agencies" by M. Ziegler, E. R. Weinerman, and M. I. Roemer, 1947 (Box 64, Folder 151)
  - A saúde e o automóvel, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 152)
  - "Social Aspects of Insecurity" (notes), 1955 (Box 64, Folder 153)
  - "Social Class and Medical Care" by M. A. Lavenhar, R. A. Ratner, and E. R. Weinerman, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 154)
  - "The Social and Economic Aspects of Rheumatic Fever" (notes), 1950 (Box 64, Folder 155)
  - "Social Justice in the Jewish Tradition" (notes), 1955 (Box 64, Folder 156)
  - "Social Medicine" (notes), undated (Box 64, Folder 157)
  - "Social Medicine in Western Europe", 1951 (Box 64, Folder 158)
  - "Social Problems of Medical Care" (notes), 1954 (Box 64, Folder 159)
  - "Structure and Scope of Medical Care in Prepaid Group Practice", 1960 (Box 65, Folder 160)
  - "Teamster Health and Welfare Plans" (notes), 1960 (Box 65, Folder 161)
  - "Trends in Charges for Short-Term Care" by C. Gronvall and E. R. Weinerman, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 162)
  - "Trends in the Economics and Organization of Medical Care", 1963 (Box 65, Folder 163)
  - "Trends in the Economics and Organization of Medical Care" (early drafts and notes), 1963 (Box 65, Folder 164)
  - "Trends in the Economics and Organization of Medical Care" (early drafts and notes), 1963 (Box 65, Folder 165)
  - "Trends and Issues in Medical Care" (notes), 1958 (Box 65, Folder 166)
  - "Trends in Medical Care" (notes), 1949, 1963 (Box 65, Folder 167)
  - "Trends in Medical Care in California: Implications for Medical Education", 1962 (Box 65, Folder 168)
  - "Trends in Prepaid Dental Care" (notes), 1963 (Box 65, Folder 169)
  - "U.S. Policy and Our Atomic Future" (notes), 1960 (Box 65, Folder 170)
  - "U.S. Proposals" [their impact on group health plans] (printed in Proceedings of the Group Health Institute), 1964 (Box 65, Folder 171)
  - "Viewpoint… on Progress in Care of the Aged", 1967 (Box 66, Folder 172)
  - "What is ' Good ' Medical Care?", 1950 (Box 66, Folder 173)
  - "What is Medical Care?", 1954 (Box 66, Folder 174)
  - "What is Medical Care?" (notes), 1958 (Box 66, Folder 175)
  - "Why Do We Work?", 1954 (Box 66, Folder 176)
  - "Work, Women, and Welfare" (notes), 1963 (Box 66, Folder 177)
  - "Yale Studies in Ambulatory Medical Care," abstract of paper on characteristics of hospital out-patients and patterns of use of clinics, 1969 (Box 66, Folder 178)
  - "Yale Studies in Ambulatory Medical Care: Determinants of Use of Hospital Emergency Services" by E. R. Weinerman, R. S. Ratner, A. Robbins, and M. A. Lavenhar, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 179)
  - "Yale Studies in Ambulatory Medical Care: Effects of Medical 'Triage' in Hospital Emergency Service" by E. R. Weinerman, S. R. Rutzen, D. A. Pearson, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 180)
  - "Yale Studies in Ambulatory Medical Care: Out-patient-clinic Services in the Teaching Hospital", 1965 (Box 66, Folder 181)
  - "Yale Studies in Ambulatory Medical Care: 'Triage' System Shows Promise in Management of Emergency Department Load" by E. R. Weinerman and H. R. Edwards, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 182)
  - "Yale Studies in Family Health Care," abstract of paper on medical student response to a comprehensive care teaching program, 1969 (Box 66, Folder 183)
  - "Yale Studies in Family Health Care: Organization of a Comprehensive Health Care Program" by J. S. Beloff, P. S. Snoke and E. R. Weinerman, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 184)
  - "Yale Studies in Family Health Care: Planning and Pilot Test of a New Program" by J. S. Beloff and E. R. Weinerman, 1967 (Box 66, Folder 185)
  - list of papers on medical care by E. R. Weinerman, 1942-1962 (Box 66, Folder 186)
  - student papers by E. R. Weinerman:
    - "The Control of Acquired Syphilis", undated (Box 66, Folder 187)
    - "Control of Measles in Hartford, Ct.", 1940 (Box 66, Folder 187)
    - "How to Improve the Health of the American People", undated (Box 66, Folder 187)
    - "The Migration of the Testes", 1939 (Box 66, Folder 187)
  - commentary broadcasts for KPFA, 1949, 1954-1955 (Box 66, Folder 188-189)
  - commentary broadcasts for KPFA, 1956 (Box 67, Folder 190)
  - Federated Press articles, 1951 (Box 67, Folder 191)
  - unidentified notes, 1964, undated (Box 67, Folder 192)
  - programs and announcements (Box 67, Folder 193)
  - misc. magazine and newspaper clippings (Box 67, Folder 194)
  - "The Pains of a New Idea" by Shirley Basch (Mrs. Weinerman), 1948 (Box 67, Folder 195)
- Personal Papers and Miscellaneous, Series V; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  The material in the fifth series, PERSONAL PAPERS AND MISCELLANEOUS, has been grouped together and arranged according to subject.
  - autobiographical sketch by E. R. Weinerman, 1968? (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - biographical material on Weinerman (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - curricula vitae, 1959, 1961, 1963-1964, 1967-1968 (Box 68, Folder 3-5)
  - curricula vitae (summary), 1968 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - newspaper and magazine clippings on Weinerman and his career (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - photographs (Box 68, Folder 8)